lindinger.at 2019-12-22

# Modellbau Lindinger – The RC Online Shop

**Modellbau Lindinger GmbH**  
**Industriestrasse 10  **  
**4565 Inzersdorf im Kremstal**  
**Austria**  
**Tel: +43 (0) 7582/81313-0**  
**Fax: +43 (0) 7582/81313-17**  
**To receive free disclosure about any of your personal information, or if you have questions or comments concerning our privacy policy, please send your request to:  **[ **office@lindinger.at**](mailto:office@lindinger.at)

Thanks for visiting our website.  Protecting your privacy is very important to us. We appreciate that you do not want the personal information you provide to us to be distributed indiscriminately and this policy explains how we collect information about you, what we do with it and what control over the collection and data you have.

## Use of personal data we may collect about you

You may visit our website without submitting any personal information about yourself.  Your access data is saved to analyze and improve our offers but is in no way related or identifiable to your person.  Your personal data will only be used if you would like to make a purchase, receive warranty support, or register for our newsletter.  For the purpose of providing these service, we collect personal data about you such as: first name, last name, address, date of birth, e-mail address, telephone numbers, and payment information. 

Your personal data will only be transferred to our shipping and payment partners, so that we can deliver and complete your order. In order to complete your payment, we forward your payment information to the relevant banking institution. 

In the case you select to pay by invoice or with a credit card we may request credit information about you from our credit reference agency:

Deltavista GmbH  
Betriebstätte Karlsruhe  
Kaiserstraße 217  
76133 Karlsruhe  
Germany

We will add this information to the information we currently hold about you to enable us to make decisions about your creditworthiness and/or to detect or prevent money laundering or fraud.

We will use the information you provide you provide for the purposes described in this privacy policy to which you agreed to at the time your data was obtained. 

## Data security

It is very important to us to keep the personally identifiable information associated with our users safe.  We have implemented security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information during the order process.

We use technical and organizational measures to safeguard your personal data, for example:

  * access to your account is controlled by password and username that are unique to you;
  * credit card details are not saved, but directly received and processed by our payment service provider, “Six Payment Services (Austria) GmbH”;
  * your personal information is encoded via “Secure Socket Layer” (SSL 3.0).

You should bear in mind that submission of information over the internet is never entirely secure.  We cannot guarantee the security of information whilst it is in transit over the internet and any such submission is at your own risk.  All we can do is use all our reasonable efforts to safeguard your data and ensure that we maintain a reliable and safe environment to use your data.

If using a shared or public computer, it is advisable to logout of our website and close your browser when you have finished your user session to ensure that others do not access your personal information. 

## E-Mail marketing

If you sign up for our newsletter, we may use your e-mail address to send you information about our products and services.  As a newsletter subscriber, we will regularly send you carefully selected offers on related products from our online shop by e-mail.  At any time you may ask us to stop using your personal data for direct marketing purposes.  You can opt out of receiving any marketing communications from us by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” Link in the footer of the newsletter, with no additional charge to the base tariffs of your internet provider.  If you are already a registered user on our website, you may also unsubscribe in your “My Account” area of our website.  Additionally, you may send us an email at [office@lindinger.at](mailto:office@lindinger.at) with an unsubscribe request.

We may use your e-mail address to send you information about products or services that are the same as or similar to those that you have ordered from us and that we think you may find useful.  We will do so only if you have opted-in to being contacted for these purposes. 

## Use of monitoring tools

### Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a website analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google analytics uses “cookies”, or text files saved to your computer in order to enable an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is normally transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. In the case of the IP-anonymization on this website being activated, your IP address will however be shortened by Google beforehand within the member states of the European Union or in other signatory states to the European Economic Area Treaty. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Acting under the authority of this website operator, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports about the website activities and to provide further services for the website operator linked to the use of the website and the internet. The IP address transmitted from your browser within the parameters of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. You are able to prevent the storage of the cookies by appropriate adjustment of your browser software. However, we should point out to you that in this case you may be unable to use the full range of functions of this website.

Furthermore you can prevent the collection by Google of the data (including your IP address) created by the cookie and relating to your use of the website, as well as the processing of these data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in which is available through the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

## Product recommendations from Google

On this website, technologies from Google Inc. are used to collect and save anonymized information about the surfing behaviors of our visitors for marketing purposes.  This data is saved by using “Cookie” text files on your computer. Google uses an algorithm to analyze surfing behaviors in order to provide targeted product recommendations in the form of advertising banners on other websites (i.e. publishers). Under no circumstances can this data be used in order to personally identify any user of this website.

The saved data is strictly used to improve our offer. There is no further use or distribution of this data to third parties. Further information about the Google technology [is available here](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).  You can object to this fully anonymous analysis of your surfing habits on this website by following the directions in the previous link.

## Use of cookies

This website uses “cookies” to help better serve the interests and needs of the users of our website.  A “cookie” is a small text file with a random unique identification number which is saved to the cache of your web browser. They help to identify a user’s surf-behavior and thereby allow parts of the website to tailor specific information to the interests of the user. Most of the cookies we use will be deleted from your harddrive after you have ended your browser session (i.e. session cookies). Other cookies remain on your computer and allow us to recognize your computer when you next visit (i.e. permanent cookies). These cookies remember information so you do not need to re-enter information in forms

## Use of social plugins

### Facebook

This website uses social plugins (“plugins”) by the social network Facebook, which is run by the Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook"). The plugins are identifiable by a Facebook logo or the additional phrase “social plugin by Facebook” or “Facebook social plugin”.  
An overview of the Facebook plugins and how to recognize them is available here:  
<http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>

When you visit a page on our website that contains a social plugin, your browser will create a direct connection with the Facebook servers. The contents of the plugin will be transferred directly to your browser and embedded into the website you are viewing.  
By using these plugins, Facebook receives notice that your browser has initiated the relevant page on our website, even if you do not own a Facebook account or are not currently logged in to your Facebook account. This information (including your IP address) is transferred straight from your browser to a Facebook server in the USA and saved there.

The embedded plugins provide Facebook with the information that you have accessed the corresponding page of our website. If you are logged into Facebook, your visit can be assigned to your Facebook account. If you interact with the plugins, for example by clicking “Like”, or entering a comment, the corresponding information is transmitted from your browser directly to Facebook and stored by it. Even if you are not logged into Facebook, there is possibility that the plugins transmits your IP-address to Facebook.

Facebook can use this information for advertising purposes, market research and to tailor the appearance of Facebook pages to a specific user. To do this, Facebook creates profiles for usage, interests and connections. For example, this could be used to rate the usage of our website on account of Facebook adverts, to notify other Facebook users of your actions on our website and for other services that are associated with the use of Facebook.

If you would not like Facebook to associate the data collected from your visit to our website with your Facebook account, you need to log out of Facebook before visiting our website.

For the purpose and scope of data usage and further processing and use of information by Facebook, as well as your relevant rights and privacy & security options, please refer to Facebook’s privacy policy:<http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>

## Our contact details

We welcome your feedback and questions.  If you wish to contact us, please send an e-mail to [office@lindinger.at](mailto:office@lindinger.at) or you can call us at +43(0)758231313-0.
